[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Following the Buddha's teachings, we
chúng con theo lời Đức Phật dạy phát
vow to practice the duties of lay
nguyện thực hành bổn phận của người cư
practitioners, taking refuge in the Three Jewels and learning the
sĩ tại gia nương tựa tam bảo học lời
Buddha's teachings. We, the Tri-Buddha Association,
Phật dạy hội Trì Tam bảo chúng con Thành
sincerely offer a small donation of 500 million VND.
cúng dường với trị giá 500 triệu đồng
We pray that you, Venerable Masters, will always be
chúng con cầu chúc trên quý ngài luôn
healthy, live long lives, and
luôn được mạnh khỏe trụ thế x bà giải lâ
soon attain enlightenment, transmitting the
tu hành sớm vào thánh quả chuyển trao
Buddha's teachings to us and all sentient beings.
giáo pháp phật cho chúng con cho chúng
December 18, 2023. Recently,
sinh ngày 18 tháng 12 năm 2023 Vừa qua
Ms. Pham Thi Yen, the club leader, along with representatives of
cô chủ nhiệm Phạm Thị Yến cùng đại diện
the Buddhists in the Golden Chrysanthemum Club
các phật tử trong câu lạc bộ Cúc Vàng
practicing the Six Harmonies, respectfully offered a donation of
tập tu Lục Hòa đã thành kính dâng cúng
500 million VND to the Council of Witnesses
500 triệu đồng tới hội đồng chứng minh
and the candidates for ordination at the
và các giới tử nhân giới đàn trúc lâm
13th Truc Lam Tam To Ordination Ceremony at the headquarters of the
tam tổ lần thứ 13 tại trụ sở ban trị sự
Vietnam Buddhist Association of Quang Ninh Province.
Giáo hội Phật giáo Việt Nam tỉnh Quảng
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
We Buddhists have heard the
Ninh phật tử chúng con được nghe Đức
Buddha teach that when the Three Jewels are in the world, it is
Phật dạy rằng tam bảo trụ ở thế gian thì
like the sky with light; when the Three Jewels are destroyed, it is
như bầu trời có ánh sáng tam bảo diệt
like the sky without light. Sentient beings
thì như bầu trời không có ánh sáng chúng
suffer, are troubled, and evil deeds arise
sinh khổ đau phiền não ác pháp phát sinh
today.  The
hôm nay Ban trị sự Giáo hội Phật giáo
Quang Ninh Provincial Buddhist Association organized the 13th Great Ordination Ceremony of the Three
tỉnh Quảng Ninh Tổ chức Đại Giới đàn tam
Patriarchs of Truc Lam to preserve the Three
tổ trúc lâm lần thứ 13 để giữ gìn tam
Jewels for a long time in the world, serving as a source of blessings
bảo trụ lâu dài ở thế gian làm cội phúc
for humanity, the heavens, and all beings, including us.
cho nhân thiên và muôn loài trong đó có
Our humble offerings
chúng con phần cúng dường của chúng con
to the Venerable Masters represent our heartfelt devotion,
nhỏ bé dâng lên các quý ngài là tấm lòng
and that of all
của chúng con nói riêng và của tất cả
sentient beings, towards the Three Jewels.
chúng sinh hướng về tam
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Before the offerings of the Buddhist followers,
bảo trước sự cúng dường của các phật tử
Venerable Thich Thanh Van, Deputy Secretary of the
đại đức Thích Thanh Văn phó chánh thư ký
Executive Board of the Vietnam Buddhist Association of
Ban trị sự Giáo hội Phật giáo Việt Nam
Quang Ninh Province, representing the Venerable Monks,
tỉnh Quảng Ninh Đại diện chư tôn thiền
presided over and
Đức đã từ B hứa Khả chứng minh và Thọ
received the offerings from the Buddhist followers. [Music] Before the
nhận sự cúng dường của các phật tử hướng
Ten Masters, we
lên ngôi Tam bảo chứng minh hướng lên
pray that the Buddhist followers' wishes may be fulfilled, their
nguyện cho quý vị Phật tử Sở nguyện được
Bodhi mind may be firm, and that
viên Thành bồ đề tâm kiên
from today's offerings, the
cố mong nguyện từ sự cúng dường ngày hôm
lineage of the Buddha Dharma may endure for a long time in the
nay mạng mạch Phật Pháp sẽ trụ dày lâu ở
world. May the monks soon achieve enlightenment,
đời Chư tăng tu hành sớm thành tựu đạo
becoming the supreme field of merit for humanity, the
quả làm Phước Điền tối thượng cho nhân
heavens, and all beings, sowing seeds of precious blessings.
thiên và muôn loài Được gieo chồng phúc
[Music] [
[âm nhạc]